Maksym Shyhapov

Senior full stack developer



maksymshyhapov07@gmail.com

in linkedin.com/in/maksymshyhapov2030

Stabu iela 104-14, Latgales priekšpilsēta, Rīga, LV-1009, Latvia

+1 415 697 0941

SUMMARY

I am a Senior Full Stack Developer with 8+ years of experience in web application development, specializing in E-Commerce Systems, Enterprise apps, Health Care Systems, and Learning Management Systems. I possess excellent communication, problem-solving, and analytical skills, and I have a proven track record of delivering user-friendly and engaging websites and features for well-established companies.

EDUCATION

Riga Technical University

Bachelor of Computer Science

2013 - 2016

WORK EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Developer at Serverfarm

Jul 2019 - Jun 2023

- Designed and developed highly responsive and pixel-perfect UIs for web and mobile platforms using **React**, **Angular**, **React Native**, **Flutter** and **Vue**.
- Contributed to **CRM/ERP projects**, playing a key role in architecture and development using **React**, **Angular**, **React Native**, **Flutter**, and **Node.js**, **Python**, **Spring Boot**.
- Led the design and implementation of a cross-platform mobile app using **React Native** and **TypeScript**, delivering an engaging user experience.
- Resolved conflict issues and focus on usability and accessibility during mobile application development using **React Native**, while also designing and developing a user-friendly farming management Mobile App UI using **React Native** and enhancing **Flutter** Web by adding support for the camera, allowing users to request available web cameras, lock camera capture orientation, and capture pictures and videos with access to camera flash and zoom, and further reducing development effort by re-architecting the product using 100% **JavaScript** (**Node.js**, **React**, **Angular**), and expertly implementing and executing user interface components following **React** and **TypeScript** principles.



- Created several mobile apps with video conferences, real-time messaging, and voice-calling using **Agora SDK** and **Flutter**.
- Demonstrated expertise in Scala, Java, Python, React, Node.js, AWS, and GraphQL to develop scalable and efficient applications.
- Utilized **Angular 6**+ to build responsive web applications with a focus on shared components and reusable code.
- Developed reusable frontend components using **React**, **TypeScript**, **Redux**, and Hooks for a seamless user experience.
- Implemented DevOps procedures for **AWS** infrastructure, optimizing deployment processes with **EC2**, **Lambda**, and **S3**.

Full Stack Deve at Sellfy

Dec 2017 - May 2019

- Developed high-performance, user-friendly web, and mobile applications using **React**, **Angular2+**, Vue, **React Native** for frontend development, and **NodeJS**, **Python** for the backend with an agile team.
- Built a custom API layer to handle all CRUD transactions, ensuring proper JWT token management, and implemented interceptors to embed custom headers.
- Competently developed front-end components using JavaScript/TypeScript while
 integrating RESTful APIs into existing systems, optimizing performance and user
 experience.
- Designed intuitive user interfaces with native UI elements, including navigation drawers, search bars, and custom icons compatible across multiple devices without compromising functionalities, leading to high user engagement and satisfaction.
- Joined an ongoing project to improve the performance-optimizing with serverless architecture and increasing website traffic using **AWS**, **GCP**, and **Azure**, significantly improving overall system performance.
- Experienced in all phases of software development life cycle (SDLC) like requirement analysis, implementation, and maintenance, with extensive experience in Agile and SCRUM methodologies.
- Implemented projects by following test-driven development (TDD) using **Jest**, **Cypress**, **Mocha**, and UI testing using **Storybook**, ensuring high-quality standards and proper functioning of applications.
- Improved browser compatibility and user experience using various techniques like lazy loading, resulting in smooth and efficient user interactions.
- Structured reusable UI components based on custom design specifications to optimize coding efficiency and maintain high-quality standards throughout the project, significantly reducing the bug count by 20%.
- Proficiently used **Git** and **JIRA** as version control and tracking units, ensuring seamless collaboration with the team and effective management of code changes.

Frontend Developer at CBIT

April 2016 - Novr 2017

- Participated in the initial wave of developers learning and implementing the **React.JS** library, and consistently stayed up-to-date with the latest developments and best practices in the field.
- Successfully rewrote **HTML** to meet industry and company standards for SEO and Accessibility, ensuring a more user-friendly experience for all users.
- Tested, debugged, and shipped 10s of 1000s of lines of code to various development teams, consistently ensuring the highest levels of quality and accuracy in all deliverables.
- Introduced **Kanban** Board style ticketing system to promote highly efficient asynchronous and synchronous work, increasing efficiency by 12% and streamlining workflow across the team.
- Utilized HTML, CSS, and JavaScript, React, Angular, Vue to create 100+ responsive landing pages for both company and client, ensuring that all projects were completed to the highest standards and met all client requirements.
- Maintained graphic standards and branding throughout the product's interfaces, ensuring consistency and professionalism in all design aspects.
- Utilized **PHP** and **Laravel** for small and medium-sized projects, delivering high-quality solutions that met all client needs and requirements.
- Demonstrated high skills in writing clean and reusable code, consistently ensuring that all code was easy to read and maintain.
- Focused on improving responsibility and problem-solving skills by cooperating with project managers, and collaborating closely with other team members to ensure the success of all projects.
- Built highly responsive and pixel-perfect UI/UX with **CSS**, delivering visually stunning designs that were highly user-friendly and met all client requirements.

SKILLS & TECHNOLOGIES

- HTML / CSS / JavaScript / jQuery / Bootstrap / PHP / TypeScript / Python / C++ / Java
- Tailwind CSS / Material UI / Semantic UI / Ant Design
- React / Angular / Vue / React Native / Ionic framework / Flutter
- NextJS / NuxtJS / Redux / NgRx / RxJS / Mobx
- Node.js / Express / Laravel / NestJS / Django / Spring Boot
- MySQL / MongoDB / PostgreSQL / Amazon Dynamo DB / Cosmos DB
- GraphQL / Restful APIs
- Agile Methodology: SCRUM / Kanban (Jira, Trello, Asana)
- Version Control System: GitHub / GitLab / Bitbucket
- Containerization Technologies : Docker / Kubernetes
- Cloud Services: AWS / Azure / GCP
- Testing: Jest / Cypress / Mocha

LANGUAGES

• English - professional